An ice-swept escape route in front of them. A cold-blooded
killer behind them. The only way out is up.
The Passage is a war, action, thriller film directed by J. Lee Thompson.
During WW 2, a Basque shepherd is approached by the underground, who wants
him to lead a scientist and his family across the Pyrenees.
While being pursued by a sadistic German.
The Basque, played by Anthony Quinn.
Professor Bergson, played by James Mason.
Capt. Von Berkow, played by Malcolm McDowell.
Mrs. Bergson, played by Patricia Neal.
Leah Bergson, played by Kay Lenz.
Paul Bergson, played by Paul Clemens.
The Passage is a 1979 British action-war film directed by J.
Lee Thompson and starring Anthony Quinn, James Mason,
Malcolm McDowell and Patricia Neal.
The film is based upon the 1976 novel Perilous Passage by Bruce
Nicolaysen, who also wrote the screenplay for the film.
The film explores themes of shepherd, nazi, world war
ii, exploitation, basque country, spain.
The tone is intense.